<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tt xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/04/ttaf1"  xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/04/ttaf1#styling">

  <head>
    <styling>
    </styling>
  </head>

  <body>
    <div>
      <p begin="00:00:08.904" end="00:00:11.542">Located in Melbourne’s western suburbs the Western</p>
      <p begin="00:00:11.542" end="00:00:15.016">Autistic School serves more than just the needs of its</p>
      <p begin="00:00:15.016" end="00:00:17.942">immediate school and local community.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:17.942" end="00:00:21.155">A registered training organisation, the school provides</p>
      <p begin="00:00:21.155" end="00:00:24.629">state wide and accredited training for teachers working</p>
      <p begin="00:00:24.629" end="00:00:29.279">with children with Asperger’s Syndrome and autism.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:29.279" end="00:00:31.917">Featuring award winning design, the school’s purpose</p>
      <p begin="00:00:31.917" end="00:00:35.418">built campus is a dream come true for students, their</p>
      <p begin="00:00:35.418" end="00:00:38.004">families and teaching staff.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:38.004" end="00:00:40.982">Using more than $2 million in funding under the</p>
      <p begin="00:00:40.982" end="00:00:42.654">Australian Government’s Building the Education</p>
      <p begin="00:00:42.654" end="00:00:46.363">revolution; the Western Autistic School was able to</p>
      <p begin="00:00:46.363" end="00:00:49.211">complete its master plan, providing students, the</p>
      <p begin="00:00:49.211" end="00:00:52.580">school and wider communities with a world class</p>
      <p begin="00:00:52.580" end="00:00:56.812">training and therapy pool.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:56.812" end="00:00:59.973">Officially opening the school’s BER funded facilities,</p>
      <p begin="00:00:59.973" end="00:01:02.716">Prime Minister Gillard reflected on the significant</p>
      <p begin="00:01:02.716" end="00:01:05.406">role they were playing in supporting the school’s</p>
      <p begin="00:01:05.406" end="00:01:07.679">diverse activities.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:07.679" end="00:01:11.206">Now when you invest more than 16 billion dollars in the</p>
      <p begin="00:01:11.206" end="00:01:14.001">schools you make a difference and that’s what we did</p>
      <p begin="00:01:14.001" end="00:01:16.979">through Building the Education Revolution.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:16.979" end="00:01:20.401">We did it at a time when the Australian economy needed</p>
      <p begin="00:01:20.401" end="00:01:24.397">support for jobs because of the global financial crisis.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:24.397" end="00:01:27.793">So when it came to injecting money to support jobs we</p>
      <p begin="00:01:27.793" end="00:01:31.790">decided the best place to put it was into schools.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:31.790" end="00:01:34.533">But with all of that injection of funds and all of the</p>
      <p begin="00:01:34.533" end="00:01:38.843">new school buildings, today is a first for me because</p>
      <p begin="00:01:38.843" end="00:01:41.691">it’s the first time, under Building the Education</p>
      <p begin="00:01:41.691" end="00:01:44.407">Revolution that I have actually had the opportunity to</p>
      <p begin="00:01:44.407" end="00:01:46.184">open a swimming pool.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:46.184" end="00:01:49.005">You have innovated and used that money for a swimming</p>
      <p begin="00:01:49.005" end="00:01:52.688">pool in special circumstances where you deal with</p>
      <p begin="00:01:52.688" end="00:01:56.580">children who wouldn’t have necessarily an inherent</p>
      <p begin="00:01:56.580" end="00:02:00.577">sense of danger and the danger that water can pose to</p>
      <p begin="00:02:00.577" end="00:02:03.973">young people and also a swimming pool which enables</p>
      <p begin="00:02:03.973" end="00:02:07.447">them to have a new outlet for physical and social</p>
      <p begin="00:02:07.447" end="00:02:10.713">activity and for many of the students who come to this</p>
      <p begin="00:02:10.713" end="00:02:14.735">school having that outlet would be a particularly</p>
      <p begin="00:02:14.735" end="00:02:16.564">precious thing.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:16.564" end="00:02:19.908">With an intake of about 80 prep students every year,</p>
      <p begin="00:02:19.908" end="00:02:22.912">the school has grown considerably over the years.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:22.912" end="00:02:25.367">In addition to providing education and school-based</p>
      <p begin="00:02:25.367" end="00:02:28.946">programs, Western Autistic school supports the wider</p>
      <p begin="00:02:28.946" end="00:02:32.812">community across Victoria through a range of outreach,</p>
      <p begin="00:02:32.812" end="00:02:34.954">early intervention and professional development</p>
      <p begin="00:02:34.954" end="00:02:38.481">programs supporting teachers, children diagnosed with</p>
      <p begin="00:02:38.481" end="00:02:46.082">Aspergers and autism and their families.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:46.082" end="00:02:49.478">In her 30 years with the school principal Val Gill has</p>
      <p begin="00:02:49.478" end="00:02:51.202">seen a lot of changes.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:51.202" end="00:02:54.415">The BER funding meant that long planned amenities were</p>
      <p begin="00:02:54.415" end="00:02:57.002">finally able to be completed.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:57.002" end="00:03:00.868">It was a wish list, developed by staff for the</p>
      <p begin="00:03:00.868" end="00:03:05.361">architect, on the best features for a school for</p>
      <p begin="00:03:05.361" end="00:03:09.175">teaching children with autism and the pool was on that</p>
      <p begin="00:03:09.175" end="00:03:12.571">list, but we knew that really it wouldn’t, couldn’t be</p>
      <p begin="00:03:12.571" end="00:03:15.287">funded and would remain a dream.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:15.287" end="00:03:19.153">And then Building Education Revolution and so as a</p>
      <p begin="00:03:19.153" end="00:03:22.262">result of that, and only that, we have a state of the</p>
      <p begin="00:03:22.262" end="00:03:26.781">art teaching pool, and the dream is a reality.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:26.781" end="00:03:29.916">Parents too appreciate the significant role the school</p>
      <p begin="00:03:29.916" end="00:03:32.580">plays in supporting them and their children through</p>
      <p begin="00:03:32.580" end="00:03:33.965">their school years.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:33.965" end="00:03:37.779">For Kim Mace and her son Callem BER funded facilities</p>
      <p begin="00:03:37.779" end="00:03:40.574">have made a huge difference.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:40.574" end="00:03:44.962">The teaching pool is fantastic because my son loves</p>
      <p begin="00:03:44.962" end="00:03:49.560">water and on a sensory level he really gets a lot of</p>
      <p begin="00:03:49.560" end="00:03:53.844">benefit from the swimming and it’s been an issue to try</p>
      <p begin="00:03:53.844" end="00:03:58.964">and get swimming lessons with specialised staff that</p>
      <p begin="00:03:58.964" end="00:04:03.771">know how he works as far as learning and everything so</p>
      <p begin="00:04:03.771" end="00:04:06.566">the teaching pool is going to be just brilliant.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:06.566" end="00:04:09.439">One of the largest school modernisation programs in</p>
      <p begin="00:04:09.439" end="00:04:13.775">decades, the Building the Education Revolution is</p>
      <p begin="00:04:13.775" end="00:04:15.761">supporting children’s learning and growth across a</p>
      <p begin="00:04:15.761" end="00:04:19.286">diverse range of educational settings with positive</p>
      <p begin="00:04:19.286" end="00:04:32.665">benefits expected for many years to come.</p>
    </div>
  </body>

</tt>